Inventory of the Marna McKenzie Collection of Developing Ministries, Cooperative Ministries in Higher Education
Graduate Theological Union Archives
Marna McKenzie Collection of Developing Ministries, Cooperative Ministries in Higher Education
1964-1993
GTU 94-11-01
McKenzie, Marna
Cooperative Ministries in Higher Education (CMHE)
4.4 linear feet (4 archival boxes)
The Graduate Theological Union. Library. Berkeley, CA 94709
Marna McKenzie was hired in 1984 to direct the Developing Ministries project for the Cooperative Ministries in Higher Education of Northern California and Nevada. She coordinated resources to create campus ministry programs with local church support in schools within Northern California. These schools included Santa Rosa Junior College, Sonoma State, California State University-Sacramento, Contra Costa College and Chico State.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated by Marna McKenzie in November 1994.
Biography / Administrative History
Marna McKenzie directed the Developing Ministries project for Cooperative Ministries in Higher Education (CMHE) of Northern California and Nevada from 1984 until 1992. An ecumenical organization of Protestant communions, CMHE sought to expand campus ministry beyond its core eight schools: San Francisco State, San Jose State, Stanford, UC-Berkeley, UC-Santa Cruz, UC-Davis, Fresno State, and UN-Reno.
The committee intended CMHE to be a resource in assisting campuses to develop programs with local church support. McKenzie writes, "Developing Ministry came into being as a response to the needs of churches interested in higher education but not in the sphere of interest of existing campus ministry." These schools included Santa Rosa Junior College, Sonoma State, California State University-Sacramento, Contra Costa College and Chico State. Some of the efforts bore fruit and continued after the CMHE dissoved and became the Association of Campus Christian Ministries (ACCM) in 1995.
Marna McKenzie worked in campus ministry in Northern California for almost 25 years. From 1968 to 1981 she served in various staff and administrator capacities at Unitas in Berkeley and Ecumenical House at San Francisco State. From 1981 to 1987 she served CMHE as part-time fund raiser and assisted in public relations and special assignments. From 1984 through 1992 she worked mostly full-time directing the Developing Ministries Project of CMHE.
Along with her campus ministry work, she is a founding member of the Office for Women's Affairs in 1970, which became the Center for Women and Religion, Graduate Theological Union. She was recognized in October 1981 as one of the organization's Women of the Decade. She served on the Presbyterian synod task force on the status of women.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains organizational and program records of the Developing Ministries program of the CMHE, a Protestant ecumenical organization in Northern California and Nevada, from 1983 to 1993.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Cooperative Ministries in Higher Education.; Church Work with students.; Universities and colleges--Religion--Northern California.; Interdenominational cooperation--Northern California.
Index
Jentzsch, Trilla
McKenzie, Marna
Cavaghan, Barry
Other Finding Aids
Campus ministry: GTU 94-11-04 Cooperative Ministries in Higher Education of Northern California and Nevada Collection; GTU 2006-7-02, John S. Hadsell Westminster House Collection (U.C.-Berkeley, Presbyterian Campus Ministry); GTU 2001-11-02, United Campus Christian Ministry at San Jose State University Collection, 1960-2000; GTU 89-5-016, Berkeley Free Church Collection, 1959-1976; GTU 2003-10-02, Albert G. Cohen Campus Ministry, Social Justice and Environment Collection. Women in Religion: GTU 92-3-1, Centers and Programs, Office of Women's Affairs and Center for Women and Religion, 1969-2003.
Collection Contents
- Administration and Organizational Records, 1964-1992; Series 1; 39 folders (Box-folder 1 - 2)
  - Marna McKenzie biographical information, 1965-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
  - Campus Budgets, 1982-84 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Campus Reports and Property, 1975-89 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Compensation, 1980-89 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CID (Coordinator for Interpretation and Development) Papers, 1981-86 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - CID Papers, 1987-89 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CID Personnel, 1988-91 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CID salary, 1985-91 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Consultation March Part 1, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Consultation March Part 2, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Consultation, April 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dobbins Fund, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - DMC (Developing Ministries Committee) minutes and notes, 1983-87 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - DMC minutes and notes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - DMC minutes and notes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - DMC minutes and notes, 1990-91 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - DMC minutes and notes, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Masters for Distribution Part 1, 1984-88 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Masters for Distribution Part 2, 1984-88 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Meeting notes and reports, 1983-88 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1989-90 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1991-92 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - New Concept, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Priorities, 1980-86 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1980-88 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Publications (small), 1982-85 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Publications Part 1, 1982-88 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Publications Part 2, 1982-88 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Self-study CMHE, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Slideshow, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Timelogs, 1987-89 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - UMHE History Part 1, 1964-92 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - UMHE History Part 2, 1964-92 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Viability and Faithfulness, 1984-87 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Local Campus Ministry and Denominational Records, 1964-1992; Series 2; 36 folders (Box-folder 3 - 4)
  - Baptist, 1981-90 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chico State, 1967-84 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Chico State, 1984-87 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Collegium, 1980-87 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Collegium, 1987-89 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - CSUS (California State University Sacramento), 1986-88 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CSUS, 1988-90 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Disciples of Christ, 1985-87 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fresno State, 1981-85 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Las Vegas, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Long-Range Planning, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Long-Range Planning, 1991-92 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Methodist, 1981-83 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Methodist, 1984-85 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Methodist, 1986-88 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Methodist, 1989-90 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Quadrennial Review UCCM Stanford, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Presbyterian San Jose, 1981-89 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Presbyterian Synod of Pacific, 1985-87 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - InterPresbytery Campus Ministry, 1982-85 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Presbyterian Mission Review Guide, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Presbytery of San Francisco Part 1, 1986-91 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Presbytery of San Francisco Part 2, 1986-91 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Sierra Mission Area, 1985-91 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stanford, 1980-85 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - San Francisco State, 1983-86 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - San Jose State, 1981-86 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - UC Davis Part 1, 1982-84 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - UC Davis Part 2, 1982-84 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - UC Santa Cruz, 1983-86 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - United Church of Christ Part 1, 1981-89 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - United Church of Christ, 1981-89 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - University of Pacific, 1983-85 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - UN-Reno, 1984-87 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Unitas UCB Part 1, 1983-86 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Unitas UCB Part 2, 1983-86 (Box 4, Folder 14)